ANISHA RAJ



ABOUT ME

I enjoy designing and coding user interfaces that are not only visually stunning but also user-friendly, responsive, and accessible. It's the creative aspect of this work that truly resonates with me. My keen attention to detail leads me to discover and squash UI bugs, ensuring a seamless experience for users. I am a curious person, who is always ready to learn something new. Collaborating with others is another source of inspiration for me, as I believe that the best solutions often emerge through teamwork. Currently, I'm actively involved in personal frontend projects, while also dedicating time to a Google UX Design certification course and learning Android development.

EXPERIENCE

3.2023 - present · Personalized skill development

 Working on personal projects while upskilling through online courses.

11.2022 - 12.2022 · Geego Kids, Finland Web Developer, Freelance

- Ported mobile app into a responsive web app using REST API to fetch content dynamically
- React(Router & Hooks), JavaScript(async), CSS3, HTML5, Bootstrap
- Agile project management

3.2022 - 6.2022 · Trapesa/Filoksenia Ry, Espoo Communication Assistance, Part-time

- Interviewing and writing newspaper and web articles
- Audio-visual content for social media and website
- Finnish to English translation for website

10.2021 - 3.2022 · Changemaker, Finland Service Designer, Freelance

- Used Service Design Double Diamond processes & methods
- Performed benchmarking, surveys, and interviews
- Build volunteer personas, journey maps, prototypes

5.2010 - 1.2011 · NAPA Ltd., Helsinki

Trainee & Junior Test Engineer

- Manual UI testing and planning and executing test plans
- Automated testing of web applications and automated UI testing of desktop application
- Writing and updating user documentation

SKILLS

- JavaScript (ES6)
- Reactjs (Hooks, React router)
- HTML5 & CSS3
- SQL (basic SQL queries)
- · Linux OS & bash programming
- Git & Github
- Manual testing
- UX Design (Design Thinking)
- Service Design (Double Diamond)
- Canva, Figma, Miro, Trello
- Agile software development

EDUCATION

7.2003 - 5.2007 · Rajasthan University, IndiaBachelor of Engineering in Information & Technology

CERTIFICATION

9.2023 - present · Google

UX Design Certification

9.2023 - present • Mimmitkooda & Ōura

Android Development

8.2022 - 12.2022 · Spark Academy

Full-Stack Software Development

10.2022 · Minna Learn (Reactor Education)

The Essence of Agile Course

5.2022 - 6.2022 · Grit:lab, Paf, Åland Island

Go Programming Language Bootcamp

11.2021 - 3.2022 · Laurea University of Applied Sciences

DiversCity - Service Design Course

8.2012 - 5.2015 · Stadin Ammattiopisto, Helsinki

Vocational degree in Food Sector, Baker-Confectioner (fully taught in Finnish) (120ects)

VOLUNTEER WORK

3.2021 - Present · Filoksenia Ry/Trapesa

 Part of organizing & events developing team. Supporting administrative work

5.2020 - Present · Nicehearts Ry

• Neighbourhood Mother

4.2018 - 10.2018 · IESAF Baby & Toddler Group

• Organised weekly meetups & maintained Facebook page

LANGUAGE SKILLS

• English : Fluent

• Finnish: Intermediate level (B2.2)

• Hindi : Mother tongue







